Guide to the Fanny Simon Papers TAM.185
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Fanny Simon Papers
1927-1989
1940-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Simon, Fanny, 1903-1989
TAM.185
11.5 Linear Feet in 11 record cartons, one manuscript box, and oversize three folders.
Fanny Simon (1903-1989) was a labor organizer, economist, and socialist. Simon taught at James Monroe High School in Brooklyn and in 1936 helped found the New York Teachers Guild. She helped found the Coalition of Labor Union Women and remained active in the Guild's successor, The United Federation of Teachers, serving on its Women's Rights Committee. The collection focuses on her work as a labor educator in Latin America and the United States after her retirement from the New York school system, and her research in the socialist and labor movements in Latin America. The collection contains her manuscripts, research notes, pamphlets, clippings, newsletters, correspondence, photographs, and other ephemera related to labor unions, including issues facing teachers' unions in New York in the 1970s and 1980s. The collection also contains materials related to the International Socialist Party in the 1970s and 1980s.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in repository; provenance is unknown. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 1990.003, 1990.012, and NPA.2002.061.
Appraisal
An issue of Free Labour World from March-April 1978, a copy of The ICFTU and Women Workers, a copy of Toward Better Working Conditions for Women, a copy of Equal Rights for Women-A Call to Action, and runs of The AIFLD Report from 1966-1976, Socialist Affairs from 1973-1979, and ICSDW Bulletin from 1973-1978 were removed from the collection because a copy exists in the Tamiment Library monograph's collection. Duplicates, including a copy of "Luis Emilio Recabarren and the Labor Movement of Chile" were also deaccessioned.
Arrangement
The collection has been arranged into five series by subject and arranged alphabetically within series.
Historical/Biographical Note
Sarah Fanny Simon (1903-1989) was a labor organizer, economist, and socialist. She emigrated to New York from Poland in 1913. After receiving a graduate degree in economics from Columbia University, she became a founder in 1936 of the New York Teachers Guild and taught at James Monroe High School in Brooklyn, N.Y. Simon retired from teaching in 1963 but remained an activist in the Guild's successor organization, the United Federation ofTeachers, serving on its Women's Rights Committee. She was also a founder of the Coalition of Labor Union Women. After her retirement, she traveled throughout Latin America, training labor leaders and wrote an unpublished book-length manuscript "The Labor Movement in Latin America." In 1962 she was hired as the Program Coordinator of the Inter-American Institute for Labor Studies of ORIT (Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores) until 1965 and remained in Mexico until she finished writing a training manual for ORIT. She returned to New York but continued to travel back and forth to Latin America, for example in 1973 she took a tour of Latin America on behalf of the United States Information Agency. She was a member of the executive board of the Workers Defense League, served as the Socialist Party U.S.'s representative in international organizations and forums, including as the representative at the United Nations for the International Council of Social Democratic Women and was an associate of Socialist Party leader Norman Thomas.
Related Materials
United Federation of Teachers Records (WAG 022)
Fanny Simon Records at the Kheel Center at Cornell University (5169 mf)
Scope and Content Note
The Fanny Simon Papers contain materials related to activities Simon pursued throughout her life, mostly after her retirement from teaching in the 1962 to her death in 1989. The collection focuses on her work as a labor educator in Latin America and the United States, and her research in the socialist and labor movements in Latin America. The collection contains her manuscripts, research notes, pamphlets, clippings, newsletters, correspondence and other ephemera related to labor unions found in Chile, Mexico, Uruguay, Argentina, and other Latin American countries. Simon's interests also led to her employment with ORIT, the Latin American branch of the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (Confederación Internacional de Organizaciones Sindicales Libres [CIOSL]), where she worked to train and lead educational programming for labor educators. Her training materials are also found in the collection. Simon also travelled extensively through Latin America and met with labor and socialist leaders, her detailed journals and photographs document these experiences.
Simon was also an active member of the Socialist Party; she attended international conferences and served on committees. The majority of the materials are related to the conferences she attended in the late 1970s and 1980s, as well as her interest in the promotion of women within the party. These materials include meeting minutes, speeches, planning materials, and other conference proceedings.
In addition, the collection is rich in United Federation of Teachers materials, especially on topics Simon was interested in. As a Spanish teacher, Simon was concerned with public school budget cuts, civil rights, bilingual programs, the Retired Teachers Chapter, and the teachers in the Panama Canal Zone. The collection contains correspondence, memoranda, notes, and other materials related to the UFT's advocacy regarding these issues in the 1970s. The collection is rich in her interests in the labor movement, both in the United States and in Latin America, and focuses on the efforts made to educate activists in labor organizing.
Separated Materials
A record carton of materials appearing to be related to Mobilization for Survival Records was repatriated to TAM 127.
Clippings files.; Working class |z Latin America.; Labor unions -- Latin America.; Jewish socialists -- United States.; Labor -- Education.; Women socialists -- United States.; Chile.; Teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Labor movement |z Latin America.; Diaries; Research notes.; Coalition of Labor Union Women (U.S.); Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968; Cogen, Charles, 1903-; United Federation of Teachers; Socialist Party (U.S.); ORIT (Organization)
- Series I: Personal Materials, 1927-1986
  Scope and Content Note
  This series mostly contains correspondence, the majority of which comes from Simon's time as the Program Coordinator of the Inter-American Institute for Labor Studies of ORIT. Some notable correspondents include Julia Vigre, her nephews Gene and Michael H. Granof, American Federation of Teachers President Charles Cogen, Norman Thomas, the Latin American representative to the AFL Serafino Romualdi, Joseph Glazer, and other friends.
  Simon also kept detailed journals from her trips to Latin America, Europe, and Israel, documenting who she met and what she did on a day-to-day basis. On her trips, Simon often met with significant international figures in the labor movement, feminist movement, and Socialist Party, including Paulina Luisi, Emilio Frugoni, Oscar Schnake, Jorge González von Marées, Francisco Villagrán, and Ramón Villeda Morales and representatives from SCIDE (Servicio Cooperativo Interamericano de Educación), SITRATERCO (Sindicato de Trabajadores de La Tela Railroad Company), Sindicato Mexicano de Electricistas, Confederacion Revolucionaria de Obreros y Campesinos, SINAMOS (Sistema Nacional de Apoyo a la Movilización Social), SUTE (Sindicato Unico sw Trabajadores) and other unions. Her journals also reveal her disdain of Communists, especially in regard to Communist involvement in the labor movement.
  Photographs mostly depict images from Fanny Simon's trips, the bulk of which are from her 1940 trip to South America. Simon also travelled to Europe in 1927; the photographs mostly feature Switzerland and Italy. There are also photographs taken in Mexico and Guatemala. There are some photographs of the United States, including images of Bar Harbor, Jones Beach, Rainbow Landing, the World's Fair in New York, the Smoky Mountains, Yosemite National Park, and Yellowstone National Park. Other nonprint materials also include postcards from her trips, some correspondence from the trips, and an oversized hand-drawn portrait of Simon.
  Other materials in this series include articles written by Simon, clippings, day planners, membership cards, and other materials acquired on her travels.
  - Articles by or about Simon, 1963-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Business Cards, Latin America, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Buttons, undated (Box 13)
  - Commercial Snapshots, undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Julia Vigre and Others, 1975-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Latin America, 1949-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Mostly Related to Simon's Employment, 1950-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Personal, Teachers Union, ORIT, and Civil Service Application Materials, 1942-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1961 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1954-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Correspondence and other Ephemera, 1979-1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1962-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Day Planners, 1966-1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Day Planners, 1967, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Day Planners, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Federation of Catholic Teachers Paperweight, undated (Box Shared Tamiment A007)
  - Galleria Mueller Brochure, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Journal: Argentina, Uruguay, and Chile, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Journal: Bolivia, Ecuador, Panama, and New York, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Journal: Brazil, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Journal: Chile, Writers Conference, 1946, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Journal: Costa Rica, Colombia, Venezuela, and Cuba, 1958, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Journal: France, Denmark, and England, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Journal: Guatemala, Honduras, El Salvador, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Journal: Israel, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Journal: Mexico and New York, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Journal: New Orleans, Mexico, and Guatemala, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Journal: New York, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Journal: Peru, Chile, Argentina, Uruguay, and Venezuela, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Journal: Puerto Rico, Washington, and Mexico, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Journal: Rio de Janiero, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Journal: Santiago, Chile, Rio de Janiero and materials found in the journal, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
  - Journal: Scandinavia and London, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Journal: Spain, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Journal: Spain, Italy, and Greece, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Kingman, Eduardo, "Hombres del Ecuador" Engravings (including a personalized note to Simon from Kingman), 1941 (Box Shared Tamiment OS009)
  - Notebook, after 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Passports, Membership Cards, 1927-1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Portrait of Simon, undated (Box Shared Tamiment OS009)
  - Postcards, undated (Box 11, Folder 40-42)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Photographs: Bar Harbor, Jone's Beach, and other unmarked locations, circa 1940s (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Photographs: Guatemala, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Photographs: Italy and Switzerland, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Photographs: Mexico and other Locations, circa 1940s (Box 11, Folder 33-34)
  - Photographs: Mexico, undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Photographs: Mexico - Chicken Itza, Monte Alban, Campeche, Merida, Cuernavaca, Izamal, undated (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Photographs: New York - World's Fair and New York Teachers Guild Strike, undated (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Photographs: Rainbow Landing, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: Santiago, Chile, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: South America - Argentina, Bolivia, Brazil, Chile, Ecuador, Peru, and Uruguay, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Photographs: Travel, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Photographs: Undescribed, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: Yosemite, Yellowstone, and the Smoky Mountains, circa 1940s (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Published and unpublished materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Travel Materials, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Series II: Latin American Education and Organizing, 1920s-1984
  Series II is made up of pamphlets, fliers, clippings, articles, periodicals, newsletters related to land reform and the socialist and labor movement in Latin America, the majority of which date from the 1940s-1970s.
  This series also contains drafts and research for her manuscript, "Luis Emilio Recabarren and the Labor Movement of Chile" written in 1948-1949 under a grant from the Social Science research Council. Simon took most of her notes on index cards, which were most likely used to write her manuscript. Simon also appears to have written a manuscript on the Mexico labor movement.
  Simon also worked for ICFTU-ORIT as the Program Coordinator of the Inter-American Institute for Labor Studies. Materials related to her work with ORIT include program planning, conference proceedings, press releases, lesson plans, meeting minutes, recruitment and proceedings for the "First ICFTU World Conference on Education in the Labour Movement", their publications, Interamericana and Noticiario Obrero Interamericana, and training manuals, including her manual, "How to Teach: A Manual for the Labor Educator."
  - "Acto de Sencillo Republicanismo", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Alexander, Robert: "Labor and Socialism in Latin America", 1930s (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Allianza Sindical Obrera Clippings and other Periodicals (including Movimiento Democratico Nicaraguense and Central Latinoamericana de Trabajadores-CLAT Newsletter), 1965-1966, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - America Socialista - Organo de Comité de la International Socialista pra america Latina y el Caribe, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - American Institute for Free Labor Development (AIFLD), 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - American Institute for Free Labor Development (AIFLD) Text Outlines, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Arévalo, Juan José, "Carta Politica al Pueblo de Guatemala", 1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Argentina, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Argentina, Peru, Cuba Clippings, and Workers Education, 1976-1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Asociación de Profesores Ensenanza Secundaria y Preparatoria del Uruguay, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Asociación Magisterial de Montevideo, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Bases Constitutivas de la sociedad Cooperativa de Ejidatarios Olderos y Empleados del Ingenio" and "La Responsabilidad de los Partidos y la Representacion Popular", 1956 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Boletin del Buro Coordinador de la Internacional socialista en America Latina", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Cabanillas, Mercedes, "Algunos Indicadores de la Problematica Femenina en el Peru y las Alternativas de la Secretaria Nacional de Accion Politica de la Mujer del Partido Aprista Peruano", undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Casa de las Americas, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Central America, Costa Rica, Caribbean-Grenada, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Chile: Information Report of women prisoners, torture and other information, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Chile Labor Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
  - Chile Labor Notes: Confederation Nacional de Trabajadores, Retired Teachers Chapter, Partido Democratacristiano, "Conciudadanos del H. Senado y de la H. Camara de Diputados", 1962-1967 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Chile Labor Notes: Confederacion Internacional de Organizaciones Sindicales Libres, 1938-1964 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Chile Labor Notes: Confederacion Nacional del Trabajo, Central Unitaria de Trabajadores de Chile (CUT), Conferencia Sindical de los Trabajadores de Latino America, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Chile Labor Notes: Correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Chile Labor Notes: Instituto Internacional de Estudios Sindicales, Instituto Americano Para el Desarrollo del Sindicalismo Libre, "Labor in Chile" US Department of Labor, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Chile Labor Notes: Clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Clippings and other Materials on South America, 1946-1972 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Clippings on Socialism, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Clippings, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Clippings, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
  - Clippings on Chile, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 39-40)
  - Comunidad Iberica, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Confederacion Argentina de Maestros y Profesores; Confederacion de Maestros de la Capital Federal, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Confederacion de Trabajadores de Mexico, undated (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
  - Confederacion de Trabajadores del Peru, 1967-1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Confederacion General de Trabajadores, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Confederacion Latinoamericano de Sindicalistas Cristianos, 1963-1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Confederacion Latinoamericano de Sindicalistas Cristianos, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Conferencia de Prensa Concedida por el presidente de la Republica, Companero Salvador Allende Gossens, a Periodistas Extranjeros, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Congreso Latinoamericano de Mujere Socialistas, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Convencion Nacional del Magisterio Venezolano, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Coordinadora Nacional Sindical Departmento Femenino, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Cuba, Ministry of Education, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Current History - Latin America, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Del Partido Socialista del Sureste, 1920s-1930s (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Departmento de Asuntos Sociales Union Panamericana, "El Salario Minimo para los Trabajadores Agricolas en El Salvador", 1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - "Discurso Pronunciado por el Presidente de Venezuela, Senor Carlos Andres Perez, en la Convencio de la Internacional Socialista, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Dominican Republic Elections Clippings, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Dominican Republic - Trade Unionism including Teachers Unionism, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Early Mexican Labor Movement, a few chapters, Jewish Bulletin, 1932, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - "Educacion o Instruccion?", 1953 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "Elecciones en la Union del Magisterio de Montevideo", undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Education: Latin America "Las Luchas Sociales en la America Latina" Speech, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - El Frente de Mujeres Socialistas Populares (FMSP), Argentina, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - El Salvador, Guatemala, Nicaragua: Clippings, Articles, and other Materials, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - El Socialista, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Ercilla, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Estatutos de la Asociacion Nacional de Educadores, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Federacion Nacional de Educadores del Peru, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Federacion Uruguaya del Magisterio, Decima Convencion Anual, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Federacion Venezolana de Maestros, 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - First World Conference of the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU) in the Trade Union Movement Proceedings, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - General Education Law, Ministry of Education, Lima, Peru, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Gomez, Guadelia, "El Articulo 123 Constitucional y los Sindicatos", 1954 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Grupo Socialista Argentino de Exilados, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Historia, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - "How to Teach: A Manual for the Labor Educator", undated (Box 10, Folder 32-34, Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "How to Teach: A Manual for the Labor Educator" Draft, undated (Box 11, Folder 2-5)
  - Huizer, Gerrit, "A Community Development Experience in a Central American Village: Some Reflections and Observations", 1964 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Human Rights violations in Grenada and the Grenada-Chile Connection - New Jewel Movement, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - "Informe al Gobierno del Peru Sobre la Educacion Obrera", 1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Instituto Mexicano de Comercio Exterior, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Interamericana (Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores Publication), 1979-1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Inter-American Development Bank News, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Inter-American Association for Democracy and Freedom, Hemispherica, 1961-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Inter-American Regional Organization of Workers Executive Committee Report, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions Press Releases, 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions and Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores (ORIT), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions and Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores (ORIT) Certificates, Farewell Card, Poster of Instructors, 1962-1963 (Box Shared Tamiment OS009)
  - Labor in the Caribbean - Central American, 1964-1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Land Reform, El Salvador, 1979-1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Land Reform Pamphlets from Land Tenure Center, University of Wisconsin, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Latin America, "Comments on Pamphlet on Trade Union Organization", undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Latin America: Correspondence, Clippings, "The ORIT, Castro, and Communism", Notes on Education, 1929-1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Latin America: Peru, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Latin American Educational Conference, Antigua, Guatemala, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Latin American Teachers Organizations, 1955-1968 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Legislation and Bds. of C. and A., 1922-1933 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - "Licencias, Permisos y Justificaciones", 1970 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - List of Teachers' Unions, 1963-1967 (Box 4, Folder 21-23)
  - Lozzia, Luis Mario, Stories, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Magisterio, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Manuscript on Mexican Labor Movement, undated (Box 4, Folder 26-28)
  - Mexican Labor, undated (Box 4, Folder 29-30)
  - Ministerio de Educacion Publica, "Informe Sobre Edcuela Nacional Unificada", 1973 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Mujer y Socialismo, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Mundo del Trabajo Libre, 1962, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - "New Directions and Needs in International Labor Training" Conference Brochure, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - "News Bulletin of the International Federation of Free Teachers' Unions" and Convencio Colectivo Sindical del Grupo Exhibicion de Locales de Espectaculos, 1964, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - "News from Chilean Commission for Human Rights", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Notes: "Anarchism and Anarcho-Syndicalism in South America" and other notes on Latin America, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Noticiario Obrero Interamericano, 1966-1974 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores (ORIT), 1961-1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores (ORIT), American Institute for Free Labor Development, 1966-1971 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
  - Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores (ORIT), American Institute for Free Labor Development Photographs, 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores (ORIT) Publications, 1961, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores (ORIT) Residential Institute for Labor Studies, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 5)